<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: self | ⚔ passcod ⚔]]></title>
  <link href="https://passcod.name/blog/categories/self/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://passcod.name/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-16T22:01:02+13:00</updated>
  <id>https://passcod.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Félix Saparelli]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@passcod.name]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Django Unchained makes me laugh]]></title>
    <link href="https://passcod.name/2013/02/14/why-django-unchained-makes-me-laugh.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-14T03:22:00+13:00</updated>
    <id>https://passcod.name/2013/02/14/why-django-unchained-makes-me-laugh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It can’t be the romance. It’s above <em>Twilight</em>, but not quite <em>The Moor of
Venice</em>. It can’t be the historical value. I might not be an expert on the
years prior the <em>Civil War</em>, but I do consider myself reasonably educated, and
certainly enough to appreciate the more obvious inaccuracies. It can’t be the
suspense, of course. This is a grand tale, a <em>Tarantino</em>, where The Good Guys
Win, and of that little is left to doubt.</p>

<p>If it’s not either of these, then <em>what</em>, exactly, can it be which excited me
so that I, not once nor twice but thrice, almost stood up and really did laugh
out loud at the screen and with such a grin, what is it then which delighted
me so?</p>

<p>I attribute it to three things, because three is the magic number; beyond that
you’ll lose patience and your attention will waver, and beneath your thirst
won’t be quenched. The first thing is art, the second is art, and the third?
the third is music.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thinking about a new tagline]]></title>
    <link href="https://passcod.name/2013/02/11/thinking-about-a-new-tagline.html"/>
    <updated>2013-02-11T02:47:00+13:00</updated>
    <id>https://passcod.name/2013/02/11/thinking-about-a-new-tagline</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been thinking about getting a new tagline recently. I don’t mean “Somewhat
of a geek, but more of a techie.” That’s fine, and I’m pretty happy about it. I
mean the stuff that comes after it, not on this blog, but <a href="https://twitter.com/passcod">on Twitter</a> and
<a href="http://stackoverflow.com/users/231788/felix-saparelli">other</a> <a href="http://fictionaut.com/users/felix-saparelli">places</a> where a bio is necessary. Currently, that’s:</p>

<p><q>Makes the web, reads books, writes blurbs, admires fonts, critiques code.
Thinks &lt;3 looks like an ice-cream cone.</q></p>

<p>Obviously, for Twitter, it has to fit within 100 chars, and I have used longer
versions or addendi on sites which are less restricted. I consider this version
the ‘official’ one, though.</p>

<p>I’ve been delaying changing it, though, because I really want to include
something Mozilla-related, and I don’t think I’ve done nearly enough in any
Mozilla-related domain to justify putting something in what is essentially part
of my online identity. However, I've come to terms with it by accepting the
caveat I need to make that new one extensible.</p>

<p>I’ll probably use single words or one-unit terms separated with bullets (‘•’ or
U+2022 or ⌥ + 8) or interpuncts (‘·’ or U+00B7 or ⇧ + ⌥ + 9) depending on which
is best-looking in context and my mood at the time.</p>

<p>This definitely requires more reflexion, though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
