<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: work | ⚔ passcod ⚔]]></title>
  <link href="http://passcod.net/blog/categories/work/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://passcod.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-25T16:35:10+13:00</updated>
  <id>http://passcod.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Félix Saparelli]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@passcod.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Expectations as a Developer]]></title>
    <link href="http://passcod.net/2013/03/01/my-expectations-as-a-developer.html"/>
    <updated>2013-03-01T01:03:00+13:00</updated>
    <id>http://passcod.net/2013/03/01/my-expectations-as-a-developer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A part of my personal philosophy, a guiding principle of sorts,
if you will, is “don’t expect anything (thus anything good that
happens is bonus).” This is a perfectly good and valid principle,
and I have to say it feels pretty sweet— until you realise life
is better <em>with</em> expectations.</p>

<p>My expectations as a working man come to two simple things: get
paid enough to live comfortably, and not have dicks as bosses.
Fortunately, this tends to be pretty easy to find. My expectations
as a developer are quite a lot more thorough. My expectations as
a working developer must therefore be both of these, and maybe a
little more.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>I expect to see your tech stack, and I expect you to be truthful
about it. “Ruby” is not enough of a description. Do you mean RoR
or an alternative full-stack framework or a micro-framework or a
custom-coded, no frameworks-involved, thing? Similarly, saying
you use “Language X and Framework Y version Z” when in fact 90%
of your code is years-old-pasted-together-badly-architectured and
the other 10% is a partial migration to Y v.Z, and my job will
in fact be to help you maintain the whole and maybe convert it
later on… which brings me to my next point:</p></li>
<li><p>I expect you to tell me what I’m going to do and stick to it.
If you hire me as a developer I expect to work as a developer,
not as an “IT guy,” and I certainly do not expect to have to
repair your crapware or set up firewall rules to prevent other
employees from looking at Facebook during work. On the other
hand, if I start behaving more like a sysadmin while I should
be coding, tell me off. I’ll thank you in the long run.</p></li>
<li><p>Finally, and this might be me being pedantic: <em>if you use four
exclamation marks I’m going to laugh at you and move on</em>. There’s
various levels of irritation I get into due to poor typography
and copy, and it might seem puny, but it says something about
you and without your other redeeming features on display I will
judge you harshly. I do <em>not</em> expect you to know the difference
between <a href="https://dash.passcod.net">an en dash and an em dash</a>, and using <a href="http://www.typographyforlawyers.com/?page_id=1701">double-hyphens
instead</a> can be understandable, as well as <a href="https://twitter.com/LeaVerou/status/291333834904055809">curly quotes</a>,
but misplace an apostrophe and you’re in for trouble.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
