<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: checkthis | ⚔ passcod ⚔]]></title>
  <link href="http://passcod.net/blog/categories/checkthis/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://passcod.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-25T16:36:06+13:00</updated>
  <id>http://passcod.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Félix Saparelli]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@passcod.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sprockets on Sinatra (&amp; Heroku)]]></title>
    <link href="http://passcod.net/2012/06/03/sprockets-on-sinatra-and-heroku.html"/>
    <updated>2012-06-03T00:00:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://passcod.net/2012/06/03/sprockets-on-sinatra-and-heroku</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Original on <a href="http://checkthis.com/biye">Checkthis.com</a>.</em></p>

<p>In the world of ruby, there exists this framework called Rails, which I'm
sure you've heard about. I happen not to like it very much. One of the
reasons is that I've read maybe 2% of Rails' code, whereas for most of the
other gems I use this is more like 40%. With Rails, I rely on magic (and,
yea, it's nice) and with the other stuff, I rely on my own knowledge. I
prefer the latter.</p>

<p>There's also that Rails is an MVC framework, which is best buds with
ActiveRecord and is a pain to manage as soon as you separate them. If you
don't want or need the MVC pattern, or ActiveRecord, you're in for trouble.
If you are unfortunate enough to need a gem which is incompatible with a Rails
component, even if said component is supposed to be optional, you have my sympathies.</p>

<p>In the world of Ruby, there also exists a little wonder called Sinatra. Sinatra
is just the dispatcher part of Rails, plus the templating, plus a few other nifty
features, but done right. It's small, sharp, lean, and mean. And it does exactly as
advertised, no more, no less. When building an application with Sinatra, you get to
pick and choose. DataMapper vs. ActiveRecord vs. Sequel? A single line in the Gemfile.
Not MVC? No problem. Custom directory structure? We wouldn't have it any other way.</p>

<p>There's <strong>no magic</strong> in Sinatra (or just plain Rack, if that's your fancy). It's all
<strong>just code</strong>. And chances are you'll have written or read a lot of it.
<a href="http://wordpress.org/">Wordpress says code is poetry</a>, and I agree, but given that
Wordpress is written in PHP, I feel that with ruby... <em>code is art</em>.</p>

<p><img src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/checkthis.com/asset/4fca9c0855a70a00030025d7/4fca9c0855a70a00030025d7-medium.png" alt="Code is art" /></p>

<p>In the world of ruby, there happens to be another wonder called Sprockets. Sprockets
is what powers Rails' 3.1+ asset pipeline. And therein lies the problem.</p>

<p>Sprockets is an awesome tool, and adding it to a Rack application makes things even
sparklier than pink unicorns. But it's relatively under-documented and Googling for
solutions returns Rails-related stuff 99% of the time. Annoying. That's due to a little
something called sprockets-rails, which takes sprockets, adds magic, and transforms it
into the asset pipeline. Trying to use asset pipeline know-how with standalone Sprockets
is frustrating.</p>

<p>So how do you do it?</p>

<!--more-->


<p>``` ruby Gemfile
source :rubygems
ruby "1.9.3"</p>

<p>gem "sinatra"</p>

<p>group :app do
  gem "haml"
  gem "json"
  gem "sprockets-helpers"
end</p>

<p>group :rackup do
  gem "rack"
  gem "unicorn"
end</p>

<p>group :assets do
  gem "sprockets"
  gem "sprockets-helpers"
  gem "stylus"
  gem "coffee-script"
  gem "yui-compressor"
  gem "uglifier"
end</p>

<p>group :development do
  gem "heroku", require: false
  gem "foreman", require: false
  gem "shotgun", require: false
  gem "thin", require: false
  gem "rake", require: false
end
```</p>

<p>First, you'll need most of these. You don't need <a href="http://unicorn.bogomips.org/">Unicorn</a>
nor <a href="https://github.com/rtomayko/shotgun">Shotgun</a> nor <a href="http://learnboost.github.com/stylus/">Stylus</a>
nor <a href="http://coffeescript.org/">CoffeeScript</a>, pick and choose these.</p>

<p>Some gems are duplicated in groups. That's normal. I make use of Bundler's auto-require
facility to keep code simple, and that happens.</p>

<p>Finally, the ruby "1.9.3" declaration is a new feature in Bundler 1.2, so you might need
to install the <code>--pre</code> version of the gem. I use 1.9.3, and I think some stuff breaks in
1.9.2, so beware. If you really need 1.9.2, you'll need to fix these yourself. <em>(Note:
no longer relevant.)</em></p>

<p>``` ruby start.rb
require 'bundler'
Bundler.require :default, :app
require './config/sprockets'</p>

<p>configure do
  set :production, ENV['RACK_ENV'] == 'production'
  set :app_root, File.realdirpath('.')
  set :assets, YourApp::Assets::Environment.get(settings.app_root, settings.production)</p>

<p>  Sprockets::Helpers.configure do |config|</p>

<pre><code>config.environment = settings.assets
config.prefix      = '/assets'
config.digest      = true
config.public_path = settings.public_folder
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end</p>

<h1>...</h1>

<p>```</p>

<p>This is the Sinatra main app file. Some like to call it app.rb, I <del>don't</del> didn't
like that because the app is much more than just this file.</p>

<p>The top 2 first lines load everything in the <code>:app</code> and <code>:default</code>
Gemfile groups. That includes Sinatra and sprocket-helpers. This file is mostly
bootstrapping the live side of things, and I'll come back to it later.</p>

<p>Most of the meat of the problem is contained in the "./config/sprockets" file
we require at the top, which looks like this:</p>

<p>``` ruby config/sprockets.rb
require 'bundler'
Bundler.require :default, :assets</p>

<p>module YourApp
  module Assets</p>

<pre><code>class Environment
  def self.get(root_path, preprocess = false)
    assets = Sprockets::Environment.new root_path

    # Application assets
    assets.append_path 'assets/stylesheets'
    assets.append_path 'assets/javascripts'

    # Vendor assets
    assets.append_path 'vendor/assets/stylesheets'
    assets.append_path 'vendor/assets/javascripts'

    Stylus.setup assets

    if preprocess
      assets.css_compressor = YUI.CssCompressor.new
      assets.js_compressor = Uglifier.new
    end

    return assets
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<p>Meat indeed, but pretty straightforward. That could actually just be a function,
but I was too lazy to refactor it again after battling with it for hours. Or, it
could be duck-typed. That could work too.</p>

<p>There's a call to Stylus, there, if you want don't want Stylus and prefer Sass or
Less, just remove that and modify the Gemfile appropriately.</p>

<p>There's no lib/assets paths because I don't feel the need for them.</p>

<p>The compressors have to be passed as instances. That's one of the differences with
the Rails magic way, but it's no hassle.</p>

<p>Going back to start.rb above, you'll see that we get the Sprockets environment,
and set up the helpers, but never actually set up the serving of said assets.
That's done in two ways:</p>

<p>``` ruby config.ru
require 'bundler'
Bundler.require :default, :rackup</p>

<p>if ENV['RACK_ENV'] == 'production'
  require './config/sprockets'
  assets = YourApp::Assets::Environment.get File.realdirpath('.')
  map('/assets') { run assets.index }
end</p>

<p>require './start'
map('/') { run Sinatra::Application }
```</p>

<p>Here we go. If we're in development (use <a href="http://ddollar.github.com/foreman/#RUNNING">the .env and Foreman</a>),
run the live Sprockets server. Otherwise, don't. For production, we do this:</p>

<p>``` ruby Rakefile
require './config/sprockets'
require './config/precompiler'
require 'fileutils'
require 'json'
require 'yaml'</p>

<p>namespace :assets do
  root = File.realdirpath('.')</p>

<p>  desc 'Precompile assets for production'
  task :precompile => :clean do</p>

<pre><code>assets = YourApp::Assets::Environment.get root, ENV['RACK_ENV'] == 'production'
precompiler = YourApp::Assets::Compiler.new sprockets: assets, precompile: [ /\./ ]

print 'Precompiling assets... '
precompiler.compile
puts 'DONE'

print 'Generating asset manifests... '
asset_list = {}
assets.each_logical_path do |logical_path|
  if asset = assets.find_asset(logical_path)
    asset_list[logical_path] = '/assets/' + asset.digest_path
  end
end
IO.write File.join(root, '/public/asset_manifest.json'), JSON.generate(asset_list)
IO.write File.join(root, '/public/asset_manifest.js'), 'ASSETS='+JSON.generate(asset_list)
IO.write File.join(root, '/public/asset_manifest.yml'), asset_list.to_yaml
puts 'DONE'
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  desc 'Clean assets folder'
  task :clean do</p>

<pre><code>print 'Destroying public/assets... '
FileUtils.rm_rf File.join(root, '/public/assets')
puts 'DONE'
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<p>The Rakefile takes care of the precompilation. This works with Heroku so long as the
task is named <code>assets:precompile</code>, so we're covered there.</p>

<p>I precompile everything, which might be too much, but adjust the Regexp as you want.
And then we write the asset manifests. These are to do with a pretty bad caveat which
I'll detail later. For now, we need to have a look the meat of the compiler,
in "./config/precompiler":</p>

<p>``` ruby config/precompiler.rb
module YourApp
  module Assets</p>

<pre><code># Adapted from: https://github.com/stevehodgkiss/guard-sprockets2
class Compiler
  def initialize(options = {})
    configure(options)
    @target = Pathname.new(@assets_path)
  end

  def clean
    FileUtils.rm_rf @assets_path, :secure =&gt; true
  end

  def compile
    @sprockets.send(:expire_index!)
    success = true
    @precompile.each do |path|
      @sprockets.each_logical_path do |logical_path|
        next unless path_matches?(path, logical_path)

        if asset = @sprockets.find_asset(logical_path)
          success = compile_asset(asset)
          break unless success
        end
      end
    end
    success
  end

  protected

  def compile_asset(asset)
    filename = @digest ? @target.join(asset.digest_path) : @target.join(asset.logical_path)

    FileUtils.mkdir_p filename.dirname
    asset.write_to(filename)
    asset.write_to("#{filename}.gz") if @gz &amp;&amp; filename.to_s =~ /\.(css|js)$/
    true
  rescue =&gt; e
    puts unless ENV["GUARD_ENV"] == "test"
    UI.error e.message.gsub(/^Error: /, '')
    false
  end

  def path_matches?(path, logical_path)
    if path.is_a?(Regexp)
      path.match(logical_path)
    else
      File.fnmatch(path.to_s, logical_path)
    end
  end

  def configure(options)
    @sprockets = options[:sprockets]
    @assets_path = options[:assets_path]
    @precompile = options[:precompile]
    @digest = options[:digest]
    @gz = options[:gz]
    set_defaults
  end

  def set_defaults
    if defined?(Rails)
      @sprockets ||= Rails.application.assets
      @assets_path ||= File.join(Rails.public_path, Rails.application.config.assets.prefix)
      @precompile ||= Rails.application.config.assets.precompile
    else
      @assets_path ||= "#{Dir.pwd}/public/assets"
      @precompile ||= [ /\w+\.(?!js|css).+/, /application.(css|js)$/ ]
    end
    @digest = true if @digest.nil?
    @gz = true if @gz.nil?
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
```</p>

<p>It's really just a straight copy-paste from the <a href="https://github.com/stevehodgkiss/guard-sprockets2">guard-sprockets2</a>
code. See that compile function? That's where the code to make the asset manifests comes from.</p>

<p>Speaking of which, when we're in development, we also need those manifests, so add this to your routes:</p>

<p>``` ruby routes.rb</p>

<h1>...</h1>

<p>if !settings.production
  get '/asset_manifest.:format' do</p>

<pre><code>asset_list = {}
settings.assets.each_logical_path do |logical_path|
  if asset = settings.assets.find_asset(logical_path)
    asset_list[logical_path] = '/assets/' + asset.digest_path
end
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  if params[:format] == 'json'</p>

<pre><code>JSON.generate asset_list
</code></pre>

<p>  elsif params[:format] == 'yml'</p>

<pre><code>asset_list.to_yaml
</code></pre>

<p>  else</p>

<pre><code>'ASSETS='+JSON.generate(asset_list)
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end</p>

<h1>...</h1>

<p>```</p>

<p>And you should also set up your helpers:</p>

<p>``` ruby helpers.rb
helpers do
  # ...</p>

<p>  def meta_charset</p>

<pre><code>'&lt;meta charset="UTF-8"&gt;'
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  def stylesheet(s)</p>

<pre><code>s = asset_path(s+'.css') unless s =~ /^(https?:\/)?\//
"&lt;link rel=\"stylesheet\" href=\"#{s}\"&gt;"
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  def javascript(s)</p>

<pre><code>s = asset_path(s+'.js') unless s =~ /^(https?:\/)?\//
"&lt;script src=\"#{s}\"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;"
</code></pre>

<p>  end</p>

<p>  include Sprockets::Helpers
end
```</p>

<h2>Caveats</h2>

<p>There's two biggies here:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>No image assets.</strong>
I don't think that's too much bad, because unless you want to use automated
sprite generation, you can safely relocate your images to public/ and fix your
paths. Apart from that, you'll also have to say goodbye to Sprockets' cache-busting,
but I'm sure you'll survive. Or find an alternative.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>No asset_path helpers in assets</strong>
Slightly more annoying, and the reason for the manifests. You can't use erb nor eco
nor ejs, and therefore, you can't use asset_path helpers in assets. You still have
them in your views, though.</p></li>
</ol>


<h2>The Code</h2>

<p>The <em>original</em> code samples above were all images, and that was mostly intentional. It was
so you couldn't copy-paste stuff. Learn, sheeple!</p>

<p>More seriously, checkthis.com doesn't support code listings, so that was all I could do at
the time. I had also provided a link to the original project of mine that implemented this,
but I destroyed this a while back.</p>

<p>For this reason, when I did the migration over to Octopress, I <em>manually copied and typed</em>
all the code samples. Thus there might be typos, so if it doesn't work, look around. And don't
forget to comment back so I can fix it here, too!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Minimalist Date Format]]></title>
    <link href="http://passcod.net/2012/03/17/the-minimalist-date-format.html"/>
    <updated>2012-03-17T17:17:00+13:00</updated>
    <id>http://passcod.net/2012/03/17/the-minimalist-date-format</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Original on <a href="http://checkthis.com/7qf4">Checkthis.com</a></em></p>

<p>The Minimalist date format is a 5- or 7- digits number which represents a date (no time).
It increases mathematically (i.e. you can compare whether a date precedes another by
comparing if one number is smaller than the other), and it looks cryptic to the ignorant.</p>

<p>It is made of (in that order):</p>

<ol>
<li>the 2- or 4- digit year,</li>
<li>the 2-digit ISO week number, and</li>
<li>the 1-digit ISO week day number.</li>
</ol>


<p>All these are zero padded, thus the resulting number is always 5 or 7 digits long.</p>

<p>I use it in various places, including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Some version numbers</li>
<li>Artwork</li>
<li>Weechat</li>
<li>Here</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/images/blog/h3Ml1.png" alt="Weechat date/time" /></p>

<p>Note: <em>Using strftime (from unix's <code>date</code> or the C utility, and its incarnation in many other languages), that format
can be expressed as <code>%Y%W%u</code>. Do not use <code>%w</code> with <code>%W</code>, it breaks the mathematical continuity.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Undo-Version-Control]]></title>
    <link href="http://passcod.net/2012/03/12/undo-version-control.html"/>
    <updated>2012-03-12T00:00:00+13:00</updated>
    <id>http://passcod.net/2012/03/12/undo-version-control</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Original on <a href="http://checkthis.com/l7p8">Checkthis.com</a></em></p>

<p><em>Edit (12507): As <a href="http://checkthis.com/user/makoyass">mako yass</a> pointed out, this already exists…
in vim. Oh, and there's also <a href="http://e-texteditor.com/blog/2006/making-undo-usable">an Emacs mode</a>
that copies that ability. The E editor for Windows <a href="http://e-texteditor.com/blog/2006/making-undo-usable">also has it</a>.
There's an open <a href="http://sublimetext.userecho.com/topic/92833-undo-trees/">feature request</a> for
Sublime Text, and I'm thinking of implementing it for <a href="http://codemirror.net/">CodeMirror</a>. At
the time I wrote this page, I didn't have the right terminology… this is called an <strong>undo tree</strong>.</em></p>

<hr />

<p>The littlest things tend to get very interesting if you look closely
enough. Take the world, for example: an altogether boring place to be,
for sure, but the little things that make it work are altogether fascinating. Ask Higgs.</p>

<p>I was happily cogitating when my mind came to wonder about the inner
workings of two very different but very similar things: Git and Undo.
If you don't know what I'm talking about, <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=git">google “git”</a>
or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Git_%28software%29">look on Wikipedia</a> or
<a href="http://www-cs-students.stanford.edu/%7Eblynn/gitmagic/">read this book</a>.
I assume everybody is familiar with the Undo button in <del>all</del> many applications.</p>

<p>Now, the way I see it, Undo works by pushing past actions onto a stack. Imagine you're
typing an #unblog entry in a very primitive text editor. You start a paragraph (0), type
'It' (1), decide against it, press Ctrl-Z twice (2), type 'The' (3), pause for a second,
press Ctrl-Z thrice (4), and type 'I was' (5) then go on writing. In a "classical" undo
mechanism, here's what happens:</p>

<!--more-->


<ol>
<li>'I', 't' get pushed to the stack</li>
<li>'t', 'I' get popped off</li>
<li>'T', 'h', 'e' get pushed on</li>
<li>'e', 'h', 'T' get popped off</li>
<li>'I', '_', 'w', 'a', 's' and the rest of your entry get pushed on</li>
</ol>


<p>This is cool, but it's awfully linear. What if you write a paragraph, Ctrl-Z it out,
write another one, then realise the first one was miles better? With this linear stack,
there's nothing you can do other than try to piece back things from your (poor) memory.</p>

<p>I think it would be cool to have git-style version control for your undo history. Actually,
it would be completely mind-blowing and friggin' wonder-inducing, but I'm trying to keep
myself controlled so I can type this up instead of jumping around gleefully.</p>

<p>With undo-version-control, the little scenario above would look like:</p>

<ol>
<li>'I', 't' get pushed to history</li>
<li>The current state (<em>HEAD</em> in git-speak) gets rolled back to 't', then 'I'</li>
<li>'T', 'h', 'e' get pushed to a new history branch</li>
<li><em>HEAD</em> is rolled back to 'e', 'h', 'T'</li>
<li>We are now on the original branch, and go downstream by one step (to 'I'),
then branch off and '_', 'w', 'a', 's' and the rest of it get pushed to that new branch.</li>
</ol>


<p>A bit more complex, for sure. To give you an idea, here's how it would look, tree wise:</p>

<p><img src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/checkthis.com/asset/4f5f4550dd5de200010013aa/4f5f4550dd5de200010013aa-medium.png" alt="tree-like-structure" /></p>

<p>Now imagine you write a paragraph, Ctrl-Z it, write another worse one, and want to go back. Well: you can. And also...</p>

<ul>
<li>Realise that the second one was <em>actually</em> better, and go back again</li>
<li>Merge branches together</li>
<li>Tag particular points in the history</li>
<li><strong>Rebase</strong> the fuck out of it all</li>
<li>Melt your brains</li>
</ul>


<p>Way!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
