<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: public-domain | ⚔ passcod ⚔]]></title>
  <link href="http://passcod.net/blog/categories/public-domain/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://passcod.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-06T10:09:47+13:00</updated>
  <id>http://passcod.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Félix Saparelli]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[me@passcod.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unlicensing Everything]]></title>
    <link href="http://passcod.net/2012/11/07/unlicensing-everything-because-mit-aint-enough.html"/>
    <updated>2012-11-07T21:00:00+13:00</updated>
    <id>http://passcod.net/2012/11/07/unlicensing-everything-because-mit-aint-enough</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the license under which my code and content, here and everywhere else, is published
under by default:</p>

<blockquote><p>All text and code and bytes and images that I have and will author, barring any contrary notice on
or joined to the work in question, or a global notice published here on <strong>passcod.net</strong>
(which would apply to all future works &mdash; one cannot, after all, un-release something), is hereby
released in the Public Domain, or licensed under <a href="http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">CC0</a>
or <a href="http://unlicense.org">the Unlicense</a>, whichever gives <strong>you</strong> the most rights.</p></blockquote>

<!--more-->


<p>Now, <em>what does it mean</em>?</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Most of my significant work already has an attached notice, and thus is governed by that notice,
not by the blurb above.</p></li>
<li><p>Every new project/repo that doesn't have a license notice is released in the Public Domain by default.</p></li>
<li><p>Most of my gists and code snippets out and about on the web are now released in the Public Domain.</p></li>
<li><p>All the content I have written, and will write, here (on this site/blog) is released in the Public Domain.</p></li>
<li><p>Whatever I have written to websites (e.g. Facebook, StackOverflow, Wikipedia, Twitter…) that have T&amp;Cs
which regulate the ownership and licensing of content is not affected by the above.</p></li>
<li><p>If I later say so, all <em>future</em> work can be licensed again (not released in the PD), but not <em>past</em>
work (that are released now and forever).</p></li>
<li><p>Octopress (on which this website runs) is MIT licensed (and remains so), but all code I have added to it
is Public Domain (i.e. if you run a diff between the master branch of this repo and the octopress
main repo, you should get only code I have authored, and thus code that is released. Although that's not
an exact procedure. But you get the meaning).</p></li>
<li><p>When I contribute to open source projects, my code and content is governed by whatever license that
project uses.</p></li>
<li><p>When I write code for work (i.e. commercial), it is governed (and owned) by that company.
So: no worries, boss! :)</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
